longtallsally.com 2018-08-17

# 

## **PRIVACY POLICY**

1\. Identity and contact details of the controller 

2\. Contact details of our data protection officer

3\. Data processing for fulfilling of contract and correspondance

4\. Data processing for customer care 

5\. Careers

6\. E-mail newsletter and advertising

7\. Website

8\. Cookies and similar technologies

9\. Social media plugins

10\. Recipients of data 

11\. Storage period

12\. Your rights

13\. Right to withdraw and right to object

14\. Website security

15\. Update of the privacy policy

In this Data Protection Notice we are informing you of the way in which your personal data are processed when you use our website and order via our online shop, by phone, via catalogue or in one of our stores

Personal data comprise information referring to an identified or identifiable person. They include particularly all information making it possible to conclude your identity, for instance your name, telephone number, address or e-mail address. Statistical data, which we collect for example when someone visits our website, do not fall under the meaning of personal data.

You can print or save this privacy policy by using your browser’s usual functions. You can also download this Data Protection Notice as a PDF file and archive it by clicking here:[[PDF]](https://web.archive.org/medias/sys_master/root/h32/ha3/9619104628766/LTS-PRIVACY-POLICY.pdf).

#### **1\. IDENTITY AND CONTACT DETAILS OF THE CONTROLLER**

The so-called controller for the processing of your personal data under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) is

Long Tall Sally LTD.   
3rd Floor   
25 Camperdown Street,   
E1 London 8D   
(hereafter „Long Tall Sally“, „we“ or „us“)

BY EMAIL

BY TELEPHONE

UK Freephone 0800 107 8826

From outside the UK +44 207 1111 595 

#### **2\. CONTACT DETAILS OF OUR DATA PROTECTION OFFICER**

If you have any questions concerning data privacy regarding our products or the use of this website, you can also contact our data protection officer at any time: 

Data Protection Coordinator  
Long Tall Sally   
The Lansdowne Building,  
2 Lansdowne Road,   
Croydon CR9 2ER   
UK

Or email[ dataprivacy@longtallsally.com](mailto:dataprivacy@longtallsally.com)

####  **3\. DATA PROCESSING FOR FULFILLING OF CONTRACT AND CORRESPONDANCE**

3.1 ORDER AND SHOPPING DATA

When you order via our online shop, by phone, via catalogue or in one of our stores we collect your order and shopping data. Order and shopping data include, for example:

  * • details about the items you ordered, such as model, size, colour, price, etc.
  * • delivery and billing address 
  * • returns, exchanges and replacement items
  * • if you wish to collect from store
  * • sales ID
  * • customer ID
  * • delivery status (“sent” or “returned”)

We process your data to fulfil your order, to deliver your order and to handle returns and exchanges if applicable.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

3.2 MY ACCOUNT

When you order via our online shop you can register or create a customer account. For registration the following data is required:

  * • e-mail address 
  * • self-chosen password 

After you created your account you can log into at “MY ACCOUNT” using your e-mail address and password.

We process your data so you can view and manage your details, your wishlist, your shopping bag your current orders and your payment details.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

3.3 YOUR CONTACT DETAILS AND CORRESPONDANCE

You can provide your telephone numbers so that we can contact you quickly if there is a query on your order. This is voluntary.

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR.

You can contact us using e-mail, telephone, the contact form, live-chat or mail. We process your data including content of you messages solely to communicate with you, e.g. to solve any problems or concerns you may have.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

To assist with training and to maintain and improve our customer service we sometimes record incoming telephone calls. However this is voluntary.

If you do not wish the call to be recorded please tell the agent as soon as your call is answered. 

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR.

3.3.1 JIVOCHAT

Our website uses the JivoChat chat program, a service of JivoSite, Inc. 525 W. Remington Drive, Suite 106, Sunnyvale, CA 94087 (“JivoSite") to improve communication with visitors.

You can ask questions via live chat. For examp.le about our products or if you have problems with your order. 

In this context we process your data solely to communicate with you. 

When you use the live chat, the IP address of the device and the address of the subpage from which you access our website are recorded.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

For further information please refer to [ JivoSite's Policy](https://www.jivochat.com/privacy). 

3.4 PAYMENT DATA

You can pay your order by card or by paypal, in some locales bank transfer and invoice are also available.

Depending on the chosen payment method we securely transmit your payment data to the assigned bank or the payment service provider assigned by us.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

#### **4\. DATA PROCESSING FOR CUSTOMER CARE**

4.1 YOUR BIRTHDAY

You can provide us your birthday so that we can wish you a "Happy Birthday!". However this is voluntary.

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR.

4.2 YOUR SIZE DATA

You can provide us your size data so that we can send you details of products that would be relevant for you. However this is voluntary.

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR.

4.3 COMPETITIONS AND SURVEYS

If you take part in one of our surveys, we shall use your data for market and opinion research. We shall use them only in anonymised form and for internal purposes.

Insofar in the exceptional case as data are not evaluated anonymously, such data will be collected only with your consent.

GDPR does not apply to anonymous surveys.

In the exceptional case of evaluations with a personal reference the legal basis is the said declaration of consent under Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR .

In the course of competitions we shall use your data to run the competition and to notify the winner(s). 

You will find detailed notes in any Terms & Conditions of Participation for the competition in question.

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

#### **5\. CAREERS**

You can display current vacancies under "CAREER".

The purpose of the data collection is that of applicant selection for providing possible employment.

If you want to apply please send your CV to:[ HR@longtallsally.co.uk](mailto:HR@longtallsally.co.uk)

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

For further information please refer to privacy policy for applicants.

#### **6\. EMAIL NEWSLETTER AND ADVERTISING**

6.1 EMAIL NEWSLETTER

You have the possibility of ordering our Email Newsletter, in which we tell you regularly of the latest news about our products and campaigns. 

Should you confirm your e-mail address, we shall store your e-mail address, the time of registration and the IP address used for the registration for such time until you cancel the Newsletter.

This storage serves only the purpose of sending you the Newsletter and being able to provide your registration. 

If you do not wish to receive any further email messages from us, please write to us at 

Data Protection Coordinator  
Long Tall Sally   
The Lansdowne Building  
2 Lansdowne Road  
Croydon  
CR9 2ER

Or

click the unsubscribe link in the newsletter or email us at[ privacy@longtallsally.co.uk](mailto:dataprivacy@longtallsally.com)

When we process your data in this way, we call upon the legal basis of "the performance of a contract" (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

In our Newsletter we use technologies usual in the market by which the interactions with the Newsletter can be measured (e.g. opening of the e-mail, links clicked).

We use these data in pseudonymised form for general statistical evaluations and to optimise and develop our contacts and customer communication further. 

This is done with the aid of graphics which are embedded in the Newsletter (so-called pixels). This data is collected only in pseudonymised way, and in addition the data once collected are not combined with your personal data. 

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is our foregoing legitimate interest under the terms of Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR 

We wish via our Newsletter to share subjects with our customers which are of maximum relevance to them and to understand better what our readers are actually interested in.

If you do not wish your user pattern to be analysed, you can cancel the Newsletter or disable graphics in your e-mail program in a standard way.

We wish via our Newsletter to share subjects with our customers which are of maximum relevance to them and to understand better what our readers are actually interested in. 

If you do not wish to receive any further email messages from us, please write to us at 

Data Protection Coordinator  
Long Tall Sally   
The Lansdowne Building  
2 Lansdowne Road  
Croydon  
CR9 2ER

Or

click the unsubscribe link in the newsletter or email us at [ privacy@longtallsally.co.uk](mailto:dataprivacy@longtallsally.com)

6.2 TRUST PILOT

We will send your e-mail address to Trust Pilot [www.trustpilot.com](https://www.trustpilot.com/), who will e-mail you asking you to review your order.

This consent can be withdrawn at any time by

writing to us at 

Data Protection Coordinator  
Long Tall Sally   
The Lansdowne Building  
2 Lansdowne Road  
Croydon  
CR9 2ER

Or

email us at [privacy@longtallsally.co.uk ](mailto:dataprivacy@longtallsally.com)

<https://uk.legal.trustpilot.com/end-user-privacy-terms>

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR.

#### **7\. WEBSITE**

7.1 FEEDBACK TO OUR WEBSITE 

You can give us feedback about our website. We process your experiences during your visit of our website, your name and your e-mail address.

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) a) DSGVO.

7.2 USE OF OUR WEBSITE

Every time our website is used, we collect the access data which your browser automatically transmits to make your visit to the website possible.

These access data comprise in particular:

  * • IP address of enquiring device
  * • Date and time of enquiry
  * • Address of the website called up and of the website enquiring 
  * • Information on the browser and operating system used
  * • Online identifiers (e.g. device identifiers, session IDs)

The processing of these access data is necessary in order to make the visit to the website possible and to ensure the permanent functionality and security of our systems.

The access data are in addition saved for the foregoing purposes in internal logfiles, in order to develop our website further with regard to the usage patterns of our visitors (e.g. if the proportion of mobile devices on which the pages are called up rises) and in order to administer our website in a general way. 

The legal basis for the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) b) DSGVO.

The information saved in the logfiles allows no direct conclusion to be drawn about you as a person – in particular, we save the IP addresses only in abbreviated, anonymised form. 

The logfiles are saved for 30 days and archived following subsequent anonymisation.

#### **8\. COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES**

8.1 USE OF OUR OWN COOKIES

For a part of our service it is necessary for us to insert cookies. 

A cookie is a small text file which is saved by your browser on your device.

Cookies are not inserted to execute programs or to load viruses into your computer. 

Instead the main purpose of cookies is to provide a product or service especially tailored to yourself and to make use of our services as time-saving as possible.

We use our own cookies in particular 

  * • For log-in identification;
  * • For load distribution;
  * • To store your language settings;
  * • To note that information placed on our website has been displayed to you – so that on your next visit to the website it does not need to be displayed again.

The legal basis for the above-mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR based on our legitimate interest.

We wish to enable you to use our website in a convenient and individual way. 

We further use cookies and comparable technologies (e.g. web beacons) of partners for analytical and marketing purposes.

This is described more precisely in the following sections.

8.2 ANALYTICAL AND AVERTISING PURPOSES

To improve our website, we use cookies and comparable technologies (e.g. web beacons) for the statistical collection and analysis of general usage patterns, using access data.

We also use cookies and comparable technologies for advertising purposes.

Some of the access data accrued during the use of our website are used for interest-based advertising. 

By analysing and evaluating these access data we are able to display personalised advertising to you on our website and on the websites of other providers. 

That means advertising which reflects your actual interests and needs.

The legal basis for the above-mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR based on our legitimate needs design and continual optimisation of our website and in providing you with personalised advertising. 

In the following section we would like to explain these technologies, and the providers employed for the purpose, in more detail.

The data so collected include in particular 

  * • The IP address of your device,
  * • The date and time of the access, 
  * • The identification number of a cookie,
  * • The device identification of mobile devices 
  * • Technical information on the browser and the operating system 

The data collected are saved only in pseudonymous form, so that no direct conclusions can be drawn about you personally.

In the following descriptions of the technology which we employ you will find instructions on how to object to our analysis procedures and advertising campaigns by means of a so-called opt-out cookie.

Please note that after the deletion of all cookies in your browser or the later use of another browser and/or profile, another opt-out cookies must be placed.

In the following paragraphs we describe the ways in which you can object to our analysis processes and advertising campaigns.

Alternatively you can exercise your objection through settings to that effect on two websites: 

[Truste](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/), which provide objection facilities by many advertisers in bundled form.

Both sites make it possible to disable all advertisements at once for the providers listed, using opt-out cookies, or alternatively to make the settings for each provider individually. 

8.2.1 BING ADS

Our website uses Bing Ads, a service of Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA (“Microsoft”). 

Microsoft uses cookies and similar technologies to present you with advertisements which you may find relevant.

The use of these technologies enables Microsoft and its partner websites to insert advertisements on the basis of previous visits to our or other websites on the internet.

The data accrued in this context may be transmitted to a server in the USA and stored there.

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Microsoft has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000KzNaAAK&status=Active).

You can prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting your browser to that effect (as set out above); we must point out, however, that in this case you may not be able to use all the functions of the website in full. 

You can further prevent the capture to Microsoft of the data created by the cookies relating to your use of the website and the processing of these data by Microsoft by disabling the personalised advertisements on the Microsoft Opt-Out Page.

Please note in this case that, after the deletion of all cookies in your browser or the later use of another browser and/or profile, the objection must be exercised again.

You will find more detailed information on this matter in Microsoft’s Privacy Statement. 

8.2.2 CRITEO

Our website uses the services of Criteo SA, 32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France („Criteo“) for preference-based advertising.

While you visit our website Criteo uses 3rd-party cookies. This enables us to show our advertisements to visitors who are interested in our products on partner websites, apps and emails.

Re-targeting technologies use your cookies or advertising IDs and display advertisements based on your past browsing behavior. 

You can disable the use of cookies by opting-out on Criteo's website. Alternatively you can opt-out of interest based advertising by visiting the following websites:

We may share data, such as technical identifiers derived from your registration information on our website or our CRM system with our trusted advertising partners. 

This allows them to link your devices and/or environments and provide you a seamless experience across the different devices and environments that you use.

To read more about their linking capabilities, please refer to their privacy policy listed in the above-mentioned platforms or listed below.

You will find further information in Criteo’s [Privacy Statement](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/).

8.2.3 DECIBEL INSIGHT

Our website uses technology of Decibel Insight Ltd., 89 Worship Street, London EC2A 2BF (“Decibel Insight”). 

This solution tracks browsing behavior on the website to help LTS identify problems in user experience and focus our improvement efforts. 

Should you wish to Opt-Out you can do so [here](https://www.decibelinsight.com/optout).

For further information please refer to the [privacy policy](https://www.decibelinsight.com/privacy-policy/) of Decibel Insight.

8.2.4 FACEBOOK PIXEL

For marketing purposes our websites use so-called conversion and retargeting tags (also (Facebook pixels”) of the social network Facebook, a service of Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA (“Facebook”).

We use Facebook pixels in order to analyse the general use of our websites and to trace the efficacy of Facebook advertising (“conversion”). 

In addition, we use the Facebook pixels to play you individualised publicity messages based on your interest in our products (retargeting”). 

For this purpose Facebook processes data which the service collects via cookies and similar technologies on our websites. 

The data accrued in this context may be transmitted by Facebook for evaluation to a server in the USA and stored there. 

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Facebook has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active). 

If you are a Facebook member and have allowed Facebook to do so via the privacy settings of your account, Facebook may in addition link with your member account the information about your visit captured by ourselves and use it for the targeted insertion of Facebook Ads.

You can view and change the privacy settings in your Facebook profile at any time.

If you are not a Facebook member, you can prevent this data processing by Facebook by operating the disable button for the provider “Facebook” on the TRUSTe website mentioned above.

You can further prevent this data processing by clicking the following button.

**Custom Opt-Out**

If you deactivate this data processing by Facebook, Facebook will only display general advertisements, which are not selected on the basis of the information captured about you.

You will find more detailed information on this matter in Facebook’s Privacy Statement.

8.2.5 GOOGLE

Our website uses services and technologies of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”).

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Google has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).

You will find more detailed information on this matter in Privacy Statement of Google.

In particular our website uses services and technologies hereinafter:

8.2.5.1 GOOGLE ANALYTICS

Our website uses Google Analytics. Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to analyse and improve our website on the basis of your usage pattern.

The data accrued in this context may be transmitted by Google for analysis to a server in the USA and stored there.

Your IP address will be abbreviated prior to the analysis of usage statistics, however, so that no conclusions can be drawn about your identity. 

For this purpose Google Analytics has been extended on our website to include the code “anonymizeIP”, in order to guarantee an anonymised capture of IP addresses.

Google will process the information so gained in order to evaluate your use of the website, to assemble reports on the website activities for the website operators, and to supply further services connected with website use and internet use.

As set out above, you can so configure your browser that it rejects cookies, or you can prevent the capture of the data generated by cookies and relating to your use of our websites in the cookie settings of Google’s Privacy Statement.

Alternatively you can also prevent Google from processing these data by downloading and installing the [browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de) provided by Google (the latter does function on mobile devices). 

8.2.5.3 GOOGLE TAG MANAGER

Our website uses Google Tag-Manager. Tag Manager serves to administrate tracking tools and further services, so-called website tags.

A tag is an element placed in our website’s source text, in order for instance to capture prescribed usage data.

Google Tag Manager operates without the use of cookies. 

Google Tag Manager ensures that the usage data required by our partners (Cf. the data-processing operations set out above) are passed on to them.

The legal basis of the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR, based on our legitimate interest in incorporating and managing a number of tags in an uncomplicated way on our website.

You will find more detailed information in Google’s information on tag manager.

8.2.6 MOTIONPOINT

Our website uses services of MotionPoint Corporation, Lyons Technology Center, 4661 Johnson Road, Suite 14, Coconut Creek, FL 33073, USA (“MotionPoint”). 

This service is used to provide native language translation of our pages for our Dutch, French and German website locales.

A series of cookies are used by this service to store your language preference and manage the website session.

The cookies used for managing the session expire when the session ends. 

The language preference cookie is held longer than each session to enable the website to show the correct language on return visits by customers.

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, MotionPoint has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnIYAA0&status=Active).

You will find more detailed information in MotionPoint’s [Privacy Policy](https://en.motionpoint.com/company/privacy-shield-7b7zd/).

8.2.7 NEW RELIC

Our website uses services operated by the provider New Relic Inc, 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200 San Francisco, CA 94105, USA ("New Relic"). 

This service enables us to collect statistical evaluations about the performance of the website. 

By accessing a website containing such a plugin, a user's browser establishes a direct connection to New Relic's servers.

We have no influence on the amount of data New Relic collects with the help of this plugin and therefore inform you according to our level of knowledge.

By integrating the plugin, New Relic receives the information that a user has visited the corresponding page of the offer. 

If the user is logged in to New Relic, New Relic can assign the visit to his account at New Relic. 

If a user is not a member of New Relic, it is still possible that New Relic may obtain and store his IP address.

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, New Relic has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnIYAA0&status=Active).

If you are a member of New Relic, you can prevent the linking of membership information stored on New Relic by logging out on the [New Relic website](https://newrelic.com/) before visiting our website.

You can prevent processing by setting your browser software accordingly or by opting out on the [New Relic website](https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy)by following the instructions there.

In this case however you may not be able to use all functions of this website to their full extent.

You will find more detailed information in New Relic’s [Privacy Policy](https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy).

#### **9\. SOCIAL MEDIA PLUGINS**

Our website uses social-media plug-ins ( “Plugins”) of the social network Facebook and Google+.

Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California, 94025, USA ("Facebook").

An overview of the plugins of Facebook and their appearance can be found [here](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins).

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Facebook has acceded to the EU-US Privacy Shield.

Google+ is operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”).

An overview of the plugins of Google and their appearance can be found [here](https://developers.google.com/+/plugins). 

Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Google has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).

When visiting a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser creates a direct connection to the servers of the providers.

The content of the plugin is transmitted by the providers directly to your browser and integrated into the page.

By this integration the providers receive the information that your browser has called up the corresponding page of our website, even if you do not have an account with the respective provider or are not currently logged in there.

This information (including your IP address) is transmitted directly from your browser to a server of the respective provider in the USA and stored there.

If you are logged in with the provider, the provider can immediately assign the visit of our website to your account.

If you interact with the plugins, for example by clicking the "Like" button or making a comment, this information is also transmitted directly to a server of the respective provider and stored there. 

The information is also published on your account and displayed to your friends or followers. 

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by the providers as well as your relevant rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be found in the data protection information of the providers:

Privacy Statement of Facebook.

Privacy Statement of Google.

If you do not want Google or Facebook to associate the data collected via our website directly with your profile in the respective service, you must log out of the respective service before activating the plugins. 

You can also completely prevent individual plug-ins from loading with add-ons for your browser, e.g. the Facebook plug-ins with the ["Facebook Blocker"](http://www.netzstrategen.com/sagen/facebook-plugin-blocker/).

The legal basis of the above mentioned data processing is Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR, based on our justified interest in you sharing our contents via social media and in our expanding our reach in this way.

#### **10\. RECIPIENTS OF DATA**

Data which we have collected are passed on only if:

  * • You have given an express declaration of consent for this, pursuant to Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR,
  * • Further transmission is necessary, pursuant to Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR, for bringing, exercising or defending legal claims, and no reason exists to suppose that you have a predominant and properly protected interest in preventing your data from being passed on,
  * • We have a legal duty to pass on your data pursuant to Art. 6 (1) c) GDPR, or
  * • This is legally permissible and requisite, pursuant to Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR, for the handling of contracts with yourself or for the execution of precontractual actions which are being carried out at your request.

A part of the data processing may be effected through via service providers. 

Along with the service providers stated in this Data Protection Notice, these may include in particular computer centres which store our website and databases, IT service providers which maintain our system, and consultancy firms. 

Should we pass data on to our service providers, this data may only be used for performance of their tasks.

We select and commission these service providers carefully.

They are bound contractually to follow our instructions, have suitable technical and organisational measures for the protection of the rights of data subjects, and are monitored by ourselves on a regular basis. 

Further transmission may also be made in connection with requests by government authorities, decisions of the courts and legal proceedings if it is necessary for prosecution or execution at law.

#### **11\. STORAGE PERIOD**

We store personal data only for as long as is necessary to fulfil contractual or statutory duties for which the data were collected.

We then erase the data immediately, unless we still need these data until expiry of the statutory period of limitation for purposes of evidence in civil claims or due to statutory duties of storage. 

For purposes of evidence we must still store contact data for five years from the end of the year in which business relations with you end.

Any claims will expire, under the normal statutory period of limitation, no earlier than at this time.

Thereafter we must also store some of your data for purposes of book-keeping.

We have an obligation to do so under statutory duties of documentation which may arise.

#### **12\. YOUR RIGHTS**

Under the respective legal requirements you have the following legal data privacy rights:

  * • Right of access (Art .15 GDPR)
  * • Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)
  * • Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
  * • Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)
  * • Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)

To exercise your rights as described above, you may at any time contact us using the contact details mentioned under "IDENTITY AND CONTACT DETAILS OF THE CONTROLLER”.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for us.

You may also exercise this right before a supervisory authority in the member state you are staying, working or the location of alleged infringement. 

In UK the supervisory authority responsible is: 

Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF. 

You can exercise this right at a regulatory authority in the member country of your place of residence, of your workplace, or of the place of alleged breach.

#### **13\. RIGHT TO WITHDRAW AND RIGHT TO OBJECT**

Under Article 7 (3) GDPR you have the right to withdraw your consent given to us at any time.

This will have as a consequence that in future we no longer continue the data processing based on this consent.

Through this revocation of consent the legality of the processing carried out until the said revocation will not be affected.

Insofar as we process your data on the basis of legitimate interests under Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR, you have the right under Article 21 GDPR to object to processing of your data insofar as grounds exist arising from your particular situation or the objection is directed towards direct advertising.

In the latter case you have a general right of objection which will also be implemented by us without your stating reasons. 

If you wish to make use of your right to withdraw or object, a notification without set form to the contact details mentioned under " IDENTITY AND CONTACT DETAILS OF THE CONTROLLER”will be sufficient.

#### **14\. WEBSITE SECURITY**

The security of your personal details is our utmost concern - that is why we have taken a number of measures to ensure your details are protected.

We use the most up to date security system and our site is regularly scanned for vulnerabilities by a third party to ensure it remains secure.

We don't keep your details online, our website uses a SSL encrypted secure internet connection to protect your personal and payment details. 

This means all the details you supply and any responses are encrypted before they are sent over the internet.

If you are still not confident shopping via the internet, please call on the phone number provided under “IDENTITY AND CONTACT DETAILS OF THE CONTROLLER“.

#### **15\. UPDATE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time, for example when we adapt our website or legal requirements change.   
© Long Tall Sally – Version: 1.0, status: April 2018
